# Juliano Daniel Marcelino, M.Sc. Freelance Systems Analyst

#### **Profile**

I started my career in IT infrastructure and customer support, since then adding value in almost 30 years of IT Mgmt/Gov, consulting and teaching, across worldwide companies experience. In the last years I've been increasing hard skills both in software development and technologies (Flutter, Python, JS, Docker, Arch Linux and other distros), as well in agile methodologies and lean IT. On the other hand, the main soft skills are ethics, organization, QC-Story, teamwork, communication, negotiation and flexibility. Currently I have been focusing on software development and leaving teaching aside, so now the focus is tech and code.

#### **Experience**

02/2013 - ongoing O Uniasselvi Group

In postgraduate and undergraduate, taught both person and distance learning, as well as orientation of course completion work, in education, engineering, administration, system analysis correlative disciplines.

09/2019 - 02/2021 SENAI/SC - Jaraguá do Sul Undergraduate and professional teaching professor, in several chairs at the Internet Systems Technologist and other courses.

© 17/2015 - 04/2019 Catholic University Center Santa Catarina Professor in person and distance learning courses in Bachelor of Information Systems, Software Engineering, Analysis and Systems Development, as Administration and Production Engineering.

6.09/2012 - 12/2013 Anhanguera Educational Extension and postgraduate professor.

© Delinea Education Technology Content professor and technical writer.

■ 02/2009 - 02/2012 SENAI/SC - Jaraguá do Sul

IT and Business Management Specialist, professor, content, tutor and monitor in distance learning, coordinator of the computer architecture and operating systems laboratory.

2008 - 2009 FCJ – Cenecista College of Joinville Professor in Administration and Software Development.

2008 - 2009 © CEDB – Dom Bosco Educational Center Educator in vocational training courses in IT and Administration.

2007 - 2008 • INPG - National Postgraduate Institute
Assistant professor and educational consultant.

2007 - 2008 SoftExpert Automation

Project manager at corporate management systems and consultant in BPM tools, Project Management, BSC, SWOT, KPI, competence management, quality and strategy applications.

2003 - 2006 Datasul/NeoGrid

Consultant and project management in ERP, CRM, B2B, B2C, e/c-Commerce, VMI, JIT, forecast, kanban, and SCI.



# **Life Philosophy**

I help people (and companies) to solve problems. There is no one so expert with nothing to learn, and there no one so poor with nothing to teach.

### **Keep in touch**

juliano@jmarcelino.com.br+55 (47) 99199-4901

Jaraguá do Sul - SC - Brazil

ojmarcelino ojmarcelino

#### **Certifications**

2020 OCisco Networking Academy

Cisco Certified Network Instructor

# **Education**

■2019 UniSociesc

Masters of Science in Production

Engineering, with emphasis on

Lean IT.

2012 MBA in Teaching to Higher Education.

2008 MBA (pending diploma) in Project Management.

<sup>™</sup>2007 **O**Univille

Bachelor in Information Systems.

### Languages

pt\_PT us\_EN pt\_BR LIBRAS C2 C2 C1 C1 C2 C2 C2 C1 C1 C2 Native language A2 Equivalent